# **KYLE** MORRISON | curriculum vitae

My interests and technical expertise include design and development of virtual reality experiences, game design and development, empathy in virtual environments, web development, programming languages, digital media production, entertainment, and software engineering. Address: 117 Eaglewood Way

Athens, Georgia 30606

Phone: 573.291.8716

Email: kyle.morrison25@uga.edu

Web: kylecmorrison.com

# **EDUCATION**

### **Master of Fine Arts | Dramatic Media Production**

University of Georgia Graduation Date: May 2018 Current GPA: 3.99

# **Bachelor of Science | Information Technology**

University of Missouri Graduation Date: May 2015 GPA in Major: 3.081

## **HONORS**

University of Missouri Deans List 2014 – 2015 University of DeVry Deans List 2009 – 2011 A+ Certification 2008, CCNA – CCNA2 2008 2nd Place UPE CS & IT Showcase 2015 Best Editing MU Valentine's Day Film Fest 2015 1st in FBLA District Web Design Contest 2008

#### **SKILLS**

C, C++, C#, Perl, Java, MEL, CSS, JavaScript, JSON, jQuery, PHP, and HTML 3D modeling, animation, and rigging with Maya Virtual experiences and game development with Unity and Unreal Engine Adobe Creative Suite, Microsoft Office Suite, iLife, and iWorks products

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**3D Modeler and Programmer**, Games and Virtual Environments Lab University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia

August 2016 – Present

- Programmed VR experiments in C# and Unity
- Developed immersive 3D virtual environments and original software for researching influence factors, decision making, and perception

**Graduate Research Assistant**, Ideas for Creative Exploration (ICE) University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia

August 2015 - Present

- Created collaborative works across multiple disciplines
- Facilitated collaborative projects and proposals with faculty, students, and community members

**Peer Learning Assistant**, Introduction to Entertainment Media University of Missouri College of Engineering, Columbia, Missouri

- Provided support for students completing projects in Adobe Photoshop and Acid Pro
- Graded all projects and test material submitted by thirty students

**Audio Engineer**, Voice of Literacy

University of Missouri College of Education, Columbia, Missouri

- Performed as audio technician during interviews by maintaining audio and interference levels while recording audio with audacity
- Edited and distributed interviews for online publication by cutting audio and removing unwanted noise

**Technical Support**, The Reflector

University of Missouri College of Education, Columbia, Missouri

- Provided technology support for all students and faculty
- Checked-out, checked-in, and serviced technology equipment and resource material
- Demonstrated creative software such as Adobe Creative Suite and iLife to five classes with an average of thirty students

Web and Graphic Designer, Luebbering Photography

Holts Summit, Missouri

- Designed all aspects of the Luebbering Photography image such as the logo, business cards, magnets, and promotional material
- Managed Luebbering Photography's website and the design
- Edited photos to remove blemishes and add visual effects

Geek Squad Agent, Best Buy Geek Squad

Jefferson City, Missouri

- Assisted customers with service and repair issues
- Performed computer installations and technical support

**PROJECTS** 

Mirror World | Behavioral Research VR Experiment

Programmer and Designer

- Textured and corrected meshes on assets in Autodesk Maya
- Designed and implemented character using Fuse and Unity

Windward (Working Title) | Desktop VR Game

**Programmer and Designer** 

- Designed and programmed open world exploration game using C#, Unity, and Vive SDK
- Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya
- Implemented navigation system using the Vive SDK and C#

**Public Speaking Simulator | Desktop VR Experience** 

Programmer and Designer

- Designed and programmed game using C#, Unity, and Oculus SDK
- Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya
- Programmed multiplayer networking architecture
- Implemented hand tracking using the Leap Motion SDK
- Implemented live feedback from virtual viewers

August 2014 – May 2015

April 2013 – May 2015

January 2014 – May 2015

February 2010 – Present

February 2010 – July 2010

September 2016

September 2016

May 2016

VR Maze Racing   Android VR Game Programmer and Designer ■ Designed and programmed a maze based strategy game using C#, Unity, and the Cardboard SDK	April 2016
<ul> <li>Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya</li> <li>"in image of"   Video Installation</li> <li>Videographer, Animator, and Editor</li> <li>Rotoscoped and animated scenes using Adobe Photoshop</li> <li>Filmed and directed choreographed dance scenes</li> <li>Edited footage using Adobe After Effects and Premiere</li> <li>Created a Max MSP patch to control video installation</li> </ul>	February 2016
<ul> <li>Mimeo   Android VR Game</li> <li>Programmer and Designer</li> <li>Designed and programmed puzzle based strategy game using C#, Unity, and GearVR SDK</li> <li>Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya</li> </ul>	February 2016
<ul> <li>UGA Graduate Acting Ensemble   Website</li> <li>Web Developer</li> <li>Designed website for the Graduate Acting Ensemble at UGA</li> <li>Programmed site using HTML, CSS, and JSON</li> </ul>	January 2016
<ul> <li>Black Lives Matter Project   Website</li> <li>Web Developer</li> <li>Designed website for an undergraduate's Black Lives Matter data visualization thesis project</li> <li>Programmed site using HTML, CSS, and JSON</li> </ul>	December 2015
<ul> <li>UniVirt   Desktop VR Experience</li> <li>Designer, Programmer, and Team Lead</li> <li>Led small team in creating a virtual tour of a section of campus at MU</li> <li>Modeled and textured buildings and objects using Autodesk Maya</li> <li>Designed and programmed game using blueprints, Unreal Engine, and Oculus SDK</li> </ul>	May 2015
<ul> <li>VR to IRL   Windows Program</li> <li>Designer and Programmer</li> <li>Created an application that allowed the user to switch between a windowed Oculus application and a webcam attached to the front of an HMD with gestures provided by the Leap Motion SDK</li> <li>Designed a portable solution to allow a VR workstation to be easily transported on the user's back</li> </ul>	February 2015
<ul> <li>ShoutOut!   Android Application</li> <li>Designer and Programmer</li> <li>Created the design for an application that provided socially relevant information provided by nearby users</li> <li>Helped build UI using Android Studio and Adobe Photoshop</li> </ul>	October 2014
Professional Development	
<ul> <li>President   Idea Lab, UGA Interdisciplinary Student Organization</li> <li>Vice President   Society for Students in Animation, UGA Chapter</li> <li>Member   Georgia Game Developers Association, Athens Chapter</li> <li>Member   Association for Computing Machinery, UGA Chapter</li> <li>Member   Tau Sigma Honor Society, MU Chapter</li> </ul>	2016 – Present 2016 – Present 2015 – Present 2015 – Present 2012 – 2015